Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group, 1894-1957
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group, 1894-1957
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company
108 Linear Feet About 75,000 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States.
The collection spans the years 1894-1957 and includes newspaper and magazine print advertisements for companies which were competitors of JWT clients. Product categories include automobiles and transportation; bakeries and baked goods; beverages including alcoholic, carbonated, bottled water, coffee and soft drinks; cleaning products; cosmetics, shaving preparations and other toiletries; dairy products; food including pet foods; gasoline, oil and other petroleum products; newspapers and magazines; over-the-counter pharmaceuticals; and tobacco products including cigars, cigarettes and pipe tobacco. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Some materials are fragile and may require further processing prior to access. Contact Research Services staff for further information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Collection Overview
The collection spans the years 1894-1957 and includes newspaper and magazine print advertisements for companies which were competitors of JWT clients. Product categories include automobiles and transportation; bakeries and baked goods; beverages including alcoholic, carbonated, bottled water, coffee and soft drinks; cleaning products; cosmetics, shaving preparations and other toiletries; dairy products; food including pet foods; gasoline, oil and other petroleum products; newspapers and magazines; over-the-counter pharmaceuticals; and tobacco products including cigars, cigarettes and pipe tobacco.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
J. Walter Thompson Company
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising -- Alcoholic beverages
Advertising -- Automobiles
Advertising -- Baked products
Advertising -- Bakeries
Advertising -- Beverages
Advertising -- Carbonated beverages
Advertising -- Cleaning products
Advertising -- Coffee
Advertising -- Cosmetics
Advertising -- Food
Advertising -- Newspapers
Advertising -- Petroleum industry
Advertising -- Pharmaceutical industry
Advertising -- shaving preparations
Advertising -- Soft drinks
Advertising -- Tobacco
Advertising -- Tobacco -- United States
Advertising -- Toilet; preparations
Advertising -- Transportation
Bottled water
Dairy products
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Preliminary Description of Collection
- Container List
  - Advertising industry
    - Joint Advertising, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Advertising agencies
    - N. W. Ayer & Son, 1948-1954, (7 folders)
    - Batton, Barton, Durstine & Osborn (BBDO), 1948-1954, (1-6 of 7 folders)
    - Batton, Barton, Durstine & Osborn (BBDO), 1951, (7 of 7 folders) (Box 2)
    - Cunningham & Walsh, 1954
    - Charles W Hoyt, 1948-1953, (6 folders)
    - Lennen & Newell, 1952
    - McCann Erickson, Inc., 1951-1954, (4 folders)
    - Newell-Emmett, 1948-1949, (2 folders)
    - William Esty Company, Inc., 1950
    - Young & Rubicam, 1948-1954, (7 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1952, (5 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Aircraft
    - Boeing, 1949-1953, (5 folders)
    - Cessna, 1949-1953, (3 folders)
    - Consolidated Vultee, 1951-1953
    - Douglas, 1949-1952, (3 folders)
    - Goodyear, 1949
    - Grumman, 1949-1953, (5 folders)
    - Martin, 1949-1951, (2 folders)
    - North American Aviation, 1952-1953, (2 folders)
    - Northrop, 1953
    - Piper Cub, 1953
    - Republic Aviation, 1952-1953, (2 folders)
    - United Aircraft, 1949-1954, (6 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1953, (4 folders)
    - Curtiss-Wright, 1949-1954, (4 folders)
  - Banks and Banking
    - Credit and Finance Companies--Miscellaneous, 1955
  - Electrical goods
    - Westinghouse, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950
    - Wire Cable, 1946-1947, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953
  - Fabrics and textile proceses
    - Miscellaneous, 1947
    - Rayon--Miscellaneous, 1947-1952, (4 folders)
    - Silk, 1947-1954, (9 folders)
    - Wrinkle Resistant Processes, 1950-1951, (2 folders)
    - "Tebalized" crease resistant, 1947-1949, (3 folders)
    - Wool
      - Botany Mills, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
      - Botany Mills, 1948-1950, (3 folders) (Box 5)
      - Forstmann, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Pacific Mills, 1948-1953, (4 folders)
    - Water Repellants--Zelan, 1953
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1954, (5 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Water Repellants
      - Zelan, 1946-1951, (6 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953, (5 folders)
    - Wrinkle Resistant Processes--Tebalized, Unidure, etc., 1953-1954, (2 folders)
    - Fabrics and Textile Processes--Miscellaneous, 1954
    - Rayon--Miscellaneous, 1948-1949, (2 folders)
    - Rayon--Burlington Mills Corp., 1948-1949, (2 folders)
    - Wool--Miscellaneous, 1948-1951, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Fabrics--Miscellaneous, 1948-1953, (6 folders)
  - Film--Miscellaneous, 1947
  - Fire Protection Devices--Sprinklers, etc., 1946-1953, (8 folders)
  - Fireworks, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
  - Food and Kindred Products
    - Animal food
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1953, (8 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 8)
      - Dash (Armour), 1948-1954, (7 folders)
      - Friskies, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Gaines, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
      - Gro-Pup, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Hunt Club, 1952
      - Ideal (Wilson), 1948-1953, (6 folders)
      - Ken-L-Ration, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Milkbone, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
      - Milkbone, 1943-1950, (7 folders) (Box 9)
      - Purina, 1948-1949, (2 folders)
      - Puss'N Boots, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
      - Red Heart, 1947-1953, (6 folders)
      - SAS, 1943
      - Sergeant's, 1951-1953, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-1951, (4 folders)
    - Baby Food
      - Beech-Nut, 1944-1954, (11 folders)
      - Clapp, 1944-1953, (10 folders)
      - Gerbers, 1952-1954, (3 folders)
  - Medicines--Merck, 1932-1934
  - Greeting Cards
    - Norcross, 1946-1951, (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (6 folders)
  - Gasoline, Oils, and Lubricants
    - Union Oil Company of California, 1945-1954, (9 folders)
    - Tydol, 1940
    - Veedol, 1941
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1954, (9 folders)
  - Games and Playing Cards, 1940-1954, (15 folders) (Box 11)
  - Garden Accessories, Tools, Etc., 1944-1954, (11 folders)
    - Farming and Gardening
      - Miscellaneous, 1940-1941, (2 folders)
      - Burpee, 1940-1941
      - Davey, 1940-1941
      - Ferry's, 1940
      - Kellogg, 1941
      - Vigoro, 1941
  - Gift Services, 1952-1954, (3 folders)
  - Glass--Industrial, 1944-1953, (9 folders)
  - Household goods
    - Glass other than Cooking, 1947-1954, (1-7 of 9 folders)
    - Glass other than Cooking, 1947-1954, (8-9 of 9 folders) (Box 12)
    - Glass--Cooking, 1947-1954, (7 folders)
  - Hardware, Locks, Etc., 1942-1954, (11 folders)
  - Health Appliances, Lamps, Etc., 1945-1951, (7 folders)
  - Hearing Devices (hearing aids), 1947-1954, (8 folders)
  - Sewing Machines, 1945
  - Heating Devices
    - Oil, 1946-1954, (8 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954, (2 folders)
    - Coal, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 13)
    - Electric, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
    - Fireplaces, 1947-1953, (6 folders)
    - Gas, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1952, (6 folders)
  - Hospitals, 1948-1949, (2 folders)
  - Hotels and Restaurants, 1952-1954, (3 folders)
  - Hotels and Restaurants, 1947-1951, (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - Household Goods
    - Kitchen Equipment
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (7 folders)
      - Youngstown Kitchens, 1950
    - Mending Aids (Tape, etc.), 1945-1953, (10 folders)
    - Name Tape, 1945-1953, (5 folders)
    - Notions, 1949-1953, (5 folders)
    - Notions, zippers, etc., 1945-1948, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Odor Dispellents
      - Air Wick, 1943-1954, (10 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (7 folders)
    - Polishes
      - Floor (including mops), 1947-1954, (8 folders)
      - Furniture, 1947-1954, (9 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1954, (8 folders) (Box 16)
      - Silver/metal, 1943-1954, (11 folders)
      - Shoe, 1943-1954, (12 folders)
    - Household--Miscellaneous (including Peter Putter), 1945-1947, (3 folders)
  - Insecticides and Exterminators
    - Garden, 1952-1954, (4 folders)
    - Moth, 1946-1953, (5 folders)
    - Vermin (Flies, rats, etc.)
      - Bug-a-Boo, 1946
      - Destro, 1946
      - Miscellaneous, 1942-1953, (6 folders)
      - Aer-a-sol, 1946-1952, (4 folders)
      - Fly Ded, 1946-1950, (2 folders)
      - Agricultural, 1946
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1952, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Flit, 1945
      - Garden, 1949-1950, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1949, (2 folders)
  - Institutional, 1949-1954, (6 folders)
  - Publications
  - Newspapers
    - Chicago Tribune, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 18)
    - Hearst, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
    - Metropolitan Group, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
    - Minneapolis Star Journal and Tribune, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
    - Philadelphia Bulletin, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
    - New York World Telegram and the Sun, 1950
    - Philadelphia Inquirer, 1946-1953, (8 folders)
    - Portland Journal, 1944-1953, (9 folders)
    - Portland Oregonian, 1941
    - St. Louis Globe Democrat, 1941-1942, (2 folders)
    - Troy Record, 1942
    - Washington Post, 1942
    - Washington Spokesman-Review, 1942
    - Williamsport Grit, 1942
    - (NY) World Telegram, 1947-1954, (6 folders) (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940-1954, (15 folders)
  - Propaganda, 1941
  - Comics, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Magazines
    - Better Homes & Gardens, 1964
    - Fortune, 1964
    - Good Housekeeping, 1964
    - Holiday, 1964
    - Ladies' Home Journal, 1964
    - Life, 1964
    - Look, 1964
    - Miscellaneous, 1964
    - Reader's Digest, 1964
    - Time, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Woman's Day, 1964
  - Public relations
    - Youngstown, 1964
    - U.S. Steel Corp., 1964
    - Annual Statements, 1943-1953, (11 folders) (Box 21)
    - Employer-Employee Relations, 1943-1950, (7 folders)
    - Government criticism, replies to, 1943-1952, (7 folders)
    - Inflation, 1946-1951, (3 folders)
    - Institutional Advertising, 1945-1946, (2 folders)
    - Private Enterprise, 1947-1953, (3 folders)
    - Strikes, 1943-1952, (5 folders) (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1954, (9 folders)
    - Public Utilities--Miscellaneous, 1941-1947, (2 folders)
    - Annual Statements--Miscellaneous, 1948-1952, (3 folders)
  - Public utilities
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1954, (10 folders)
    - Commonwealth and Southern Corp., 1940-1941, (2 folders)
  - Publishing companies
    - Miscellaneous, 1941-1954, (10 folders) (Box 23)
    - McGraw-Hill, 1941-1953, (13 folders)
    - Rand McNally, 1941-1942, (2 folders)
    - Curtis, 1942
  - Real Estate, 1940-1953, (14 folders)
  - Brokers and Brokerage Houses, 1944-1949, (6 folders)
  - Reducing and Exercise, 1947-1954, (8 folders)
  - Refrigerants and Refrigeration, 1947-1952, (6 folders) (Box 24)
  - Squibb, 1952
  - Parke, Davis, and Co., 1952
  - Religious Advertising, 1945
  - Rubber Goods and Synthetic Rubber
    - Goodrich (Koroseal), 1946
    - Firestone, 1943
  - Public Utilities, 1943
  - Resorts, 1950-1954
  - Restaurants, 1950-1954, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Automat, 1942
    - Childs, 1940-1941, (2 folders)
  - Rope, 1946-1953, (8 folders)
  - Rubber Goods and Synthetic Rubber
    - Goodrich, 1953
    - Du Pont, 1940
    - Firestone, 1944-1954, (11 folders)
    - Goodrich, 1949-1954, (7 folders)
    - Goodrich (including Koroseal), 1940-1947 (Box 25)
    - Goodyear, 1946-1954, (9 folders)
    - Hewitt, 1942-1953, (11 folders)
    - Kleinerts, 1941
    - Republic, 1942
    - Seiberling, 1943-1944, (2 folders)
    - U.S. Rubber Co., 1949-1954, (7 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1948, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1954, (8 folders) (Box 26)
    - U.S. Rubber Co., 1944-1948, (3 folders)
    - Seiberling, 1948
  - Rust Preventatives, 1943-1953, (10 folders)
  - Safes, 1942
  - Scales, 1945-1954, (8 folders)
  - Schools
    - Dancing, 1950, 1954, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence schools, 1950-1953, (4 folders)
    - Arthur Murray, 1947-1957, (7 folders)
    - Correspondence schools
      - International, 1940-1942, (3 folders)
      - La Salle, 1940-1942, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940-1947, (7 folders)
    - Language, 1941-1947, (5 folders) (Box 27)
      - Berlitz, 1942-1943, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-1953, (9 folders)
    - Careers--Miscellaneous, 1942
    - Dancing
      - Dale Studios, 1947-1948, (2 folders)
      - Don Pallini, 1947-1948, (2 folders)
      - Maya Boleyn, 1947
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949, (4 folders)
    - Art
      - Federal, 1941
    - Business
      - Ballard, 1941
    - Correspondence schools
      - Dale Carnegie, 1941
  - Seeds, Plants, and Fertilizers
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1953, (10 folders)
    - Burpee, 1942-1943, (2 folders)
    - P. Henderson, 1942
    - Loma, 1942
  - Selling
    - House to house, 1949-1953, (3 folders)
    - Direct, 1950-1952, (2 folders)
  - Ships and Shipbuilding Equipment except Engines--Miscellaneous, 1944-1950, (5 folders)
  - Soap and scouring compounds
    - Oakite, 1941
    - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1941-1946, (6 folders)
    - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1922-1940, (14 folders) (Box 28)
    - Merlin, 1929
    - Oakite, 1944
    - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1935-1936, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Oakite, 1927-1939, (4 folders)
    - Pronto, 1930
    - Sani-Flush, 1931-1942, (7 folders)
    - Chore Girl, 1931
    - Sapolio, 1927-1939, (3 folders)
    - Silver Dust, 1933-1937, (4 folders)
    - Sunbrite, 1936-1944, (7 folders)
    - Sun-Ray, 1934
    - Vano, 1941
    - Volite, 1930
    - Wear-Ever, 1944-1945
    - Wyandotte, 1930-1937, (3 folders)
    - Wet Me Wet, 1934
    - Tuffy, 1954
    - S.O.S., 1942-1948, (5 folders)
    - S.O.S., 1924-1953, (16 folders) (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-1944, (10 folders)
    - Soaps--Institutional
      - Procter & Gamble, 1950
      - Miscellaneous, 1950
  - Soap and scouring compounds
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953, (5 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950-1954, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Borax, 1927-1933, (2 folders)
  - Softeners, Water, 1943-1954, (12 folders)
  - Sponges, 1950-1953, (4 folders)
  - Sports and Sporting Goods, 1941-1954, (15 folders)
  - Spray Systems--See also Fire Protection Devices, 1946
  - Stores--Bakery--Hanscom, 1942
  - Store advertising
    - Chain drug, 1951-1952, (2 folders)
    - Chain drug, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Chain grocery, 1947-1952, (5 folders)
    - Chain variety, 1947-1954, (5 folders)
    - Chain miscellaneous, 1947-1952, (2 folders)
    - Department stores
      - Altman's, 1947-1953, (5 folders)
      - Best & Co., 1952
      - Bloomingdale's, 1947-1953, (4 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950, (2 folders)
      - Lord & Taylor, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Macy's, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Best & Co., 1950
      - Saks Fifth Avenue, 1950
      - John Wanamaker, 1947-1953, (5 folders)
    - Bakeries, 1954 (Box 33)
    - Chain drug, 1950-1954, (3 folders)
  - Testimonial Advertising, 1950/1953
  - "Tie-in" Advertisements, 1953
  - Warehouses, 1950-1952, (2 folders)
  - Water Treatment Systems, 1949-1952, (3 folders)
  - Wax, 1949
  - Welfare and Religious Organizations--Red Cross and other, 1948-1953, (8 folders)
  - Yarns and fibers
    - Celanese, 1944-1953, (9 folders)
    - Lastex (United States Rubber Co.), 1948-1952, (5 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1953, (6 folders)
  - Beverages
    - A-Treat, 1945-1946
    - Blatz, 1943
    - Boller Ginger Ale, 1943-1945
    - Canada Dry, 1931
    - Beverages--Mineral Water--Canada Dry, 1935-1938
    - Canada Dry, 1943
    - Canada Dry, 1944-1954, (11 folders) (Box 34)
    - Coca-Cola, 1922-1923
    - Clicquot Club, 1924-1925, (2 folders)
    - Clicquot Club, 1926-1952, (18 folders) (Box 35)
    - Cott, 1953-1954
    - Cotton Club, 1943
    - Coca-Cola, 1920-1936, (11 folders) (Box 36)
    - Coca-Cola, 1937-1945, (9 folders) (Box 37)
    - Coca-Cola, 1944-1954, (11 folders) (Box 38)
    - Dr. Pepper, 1943-1953, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Evervess, 1946-1949, (3 folders)
    - Grapette, 1940s-1950s
    - Hires, 1919-1953, (13 folders)
    - Hoffman, 1928-1931, (6 folders)
    - Hoffman, 1932-1954, (20 folders) (Box 40)
    - Kool Aid, 1943-1952
    - Mavis, 1943/1945/1947
    - Mission Dry Sparkling, 1929-1930
    - Moxie, 1925-1945, (6 folders)
    - Myer 1890, 1947-1951
    - No-Cal, 1952-1954
    - Store Advertising--Specialty--Miscellaneous, 1952
    - Store Advertising--Retail--Chain--Grocery, 1954
  - Beverages
    - O'Keefe's, 1921-1929, (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - Old Colony, 1947/1949/1953
    - Old Union, 1928
    - Orange Crush, 1920-1932, 1940s, (2 folders)
    - Pale Moon, 1928-1929
    - Par-T-Pak, 1950, 1953-1954
    - Pepsi Cola, 1936-1945, (8 folders)
    - Pepsi Cola, 1946-1954, (9 folders) (Box 42)
    - Phillips, 1944
    - Quinac Canada Dry, 1953-1954
    - Royal Crown Cola (RC Cola), 1942-1954, (13 folders)
    - Schweppes, 1941-1954, (2 folders)
    - Seely's, 1929-1930, (2 folders)
    - Seely's, 1931-1934, (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - Seven-Up (7-Up), 1944-1954, (4 folders)
    - Silver King, 1925
    - Simpson Spring, 1929 and previous
    - Sno-Cola, 1942
    - Spur, 1941-1954, (4 folders)
    - Squirt, 1944-45, 1949-54
    - Suburban Club, 1943
    - TIP, 1945-1947
    - Tom Collins, 1932
    - White Rock, 1929 and previous-1953, (4 folders)
    - Zep, 1943
    - Soft drinks miscellaneous, 1927-1954, (5 folders)
    - Cola drinks, 1943-1954, (7 folders)
    - Fruit flavor drinks, 1920s-1950s, (3 folders)
    - Ginger ale, 1920-1941, (8 folders) (Box 44)
    - Root beer, 1918-1954, (12 folders)
    - Mineral water
      - Appolinaris, 1924-1929, (2 folders)
      - Aquazone, 1924-25, 1927-28
      - Arrowhead, 1930-1932, (2 folders)
      - Celestins Vichy, 1921-25/1938/1947
      - Corinnis, 1928-1930
      - Gerolsteiner, 1928-1931
      - Londonderry, 1920s
      - Manitoo, 1918
      - Mountain Valley Mineral Water, 1917-1947
      - Perrier, 1917/1953
      - Pluto Water, 1925-1927
      - Poland Water, 1925, 1940-1946
      - Puritas, 1929
      - Saratoga, 1925-1946
      - Shasta, 1928-1929
      - Sleepy Water, 1929-1931
      - Sparkletts, 1931
      - Miscellaneous, 1917-1936, (8 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1953, (8 folders) (Box 45)
    - Fruit and fruit flavor drinks, 1920s-1951, (7 folders)
      - Cider (primarily Wayne County brand), 1927-1929
      - Orange drinks, 1930-1940, (3 folders)
      - Nedick's, 1920s
      - Squeeze, 1920s
      - Kool-Aid, 1941-1953, (4 folders)
      - Lemade, 1927
      - Lemon drinks, 1930
      - Nesbitt's, 1941-1950, (2 folders)
      - Sumoro, 1927
      - Orange/grapefruit drinks, 1928
      - Vegetable drinks, 1930s-1950s
    - Chocolate beverages and cocoa
      - Baker's, 1926-1941, (9 folders)
      - Mavis, 1928-1929, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1953, (10 folders) (Box 46)
      - Ghirardelli's, 1910s-1933, (2 folders)
      - Nestle's, 1940-1942, (3 folders)
      - Mavis, 1929
      - Baker's, 1921-1931, (6 folders)
      - Bensdorp's, 1912-1932, (3 folders)
      - Bunte, 1919-1920
      - Fry's, 1936-1937
      - Cowan's, 1910s-1920s
      - Hyler's, 1910s-1920s
      - Lipton's, 1922
      - Lowney's, 1913-1918
      - Maillard's, 1910s-1920
      - Miscellaneous, 1954
    - Beverages--Cider--Wayne County, 1931
    - Beverages--Dietene, 1936
    - Beverages--Department Stores (primarily wines and liquors solde at department stores), 1936
    - Wines and Liquors
      - Ancient Age, 1942-1952, (3 folders)
      - Bacardi, 1936-1954, (6 folders)
      - Bellows Gin, 1945-1948, (3 folders)
      - Bell's, 1947-1954, (3 folders)
      - Benedictine, 1944-1954, (3 folders)
      - Booth's, 1942-1954, (3 folders) (Box 47)
      - Brugal Rum, 1944-1947, (3 folders)
      - Canada Dry Gin, 1933-1936, (2 folders)
      - Carstairs, 1936-1953, (15 folders)
      - Cherry Heering, 1946-1954, (3 folders)
      - Corby's, 1943
      - Corby's Reserve, 1944-1950, (7 folders)
      - Corby's Reserve, 1951-1954, (3 folders) (Box 48)
      - Coronet Brandy, 1942-1954, (5 folders)
      - Courvoisier, 1936-1948, (2 folders)
      - Crab Orchard, 1934-1939, (3 folders)
      - de Kuyper, 1941-1954, (5 folders)
      - Dewar's, 1936-1938, (2 folders)
      - Dewar's White Label, 1945-1954, (8 folders)
      - Dixie Belle Gin, 1942-1949, (4 folders)
      - Don Q Rum, 1939-1952, (5 folders)
      - Drambuie, 1941-1954, (2 folders)
      - Eagle, 1937-1941, (2 folders)
      - Early Times, 1941-1942, 1951-1953, (4 folders)
      - Fleischmann's Whiskey, 1934-1937, (3 folders)
      - Fleischmann's Whiskey, 1938-1954, (10 folders) (Box 49)
      - Fleischmann's Gin, 1935-1954, (7 folders)
      - Frankfort, 1933-1941, (2 folders)
      - Four Roses, 1934-1940, (7 folders)
      - Four Roses, 1941-1954, (14 folders) (Box 50)
      - Gallagher & Burton, 1933-1954, (8 folders)
      - Gilbey's Gin and Scotch, 1935
      - Gilbey's Scotch, 1945-1954, (6 folders)
      - Gilbey's Gin, 1943
      - Gilbey's Gin, 1945-1954, (6 folders) (Box 51)
      - Glenmore Kentucky Bourbon, 1943-1954, (3 folders)
      - Gordon's Gin, 1943-1954, (7 folders)
      - Government House Rum, 1936-1944, (2 folders)
      - Grant's Scotch, 1936-1938, 1947-1948, (2 folders)
      - Harwood's, 1946-1948, (3 folders)
      - Hennessy, 1942-1954, (4 folders)
      - Heublein's, 1942-1954, (10 folders)
      - Hiram Walker's DeLuxe, 1944-1954, (9 folders)
      - Hiram Walker Dry Martini, 1945-1947, (2 folders)
      - Hiram Walker, 1953
      - Hiram Walker's Gin, 1945-1946, (2 folders)
      - Hiram Walker's Gin, 1947-1954, (2 folders) (Box 52)
      - Holland House, 1945-1954, (2 folders)
      - Hunter Kentucky Bourbon, 1938-1954, (3 folders)
      - I.W. Harper, 1942-1948, (2 folders)
      - Jamaica Rums, 1942-1948, (2 folders)
      - James E. Pepper, 1945-1953, (4 folders)
      - Johnnie Walker, 1942-1954, (11 folders)
      - Kinsey Gin, 1945-1947, (3 folders)
      - Lejon Brandy, 1942-1950, (4 folders)
      - Martell, 1947-1954, (2 folders)
      - Martin's V.V.O. Scotch, 1943-1954, (4 folders)
      - M & M (Mattingly & Moore), 1942-1943, (2 folders)
      - Melrose, 1942-1950, (3 folders)
      - Merito, 1942-1952, (4 folders)
      - Milshire Gin, 1934-1945, (3 folders)
      - Mount Vernon, 1935-1953, (11 folders) (Box 53)
      - Myers's Rum, 1938-1954, (7 folders)